Zach Danz

FRONT END WEB DEVELOPER

MEET ZACH

I am a 29-year-old Front End Web Developer who spent six years living in Shanghai, China. I have a diverse range of skills which allows me to bring so much more to the table than just coding. I have a lifelong love of tech, languages, performance, and learning of all kinds. Currently based in the USA.

TECH SKILLS

- HTML
- React.js
- Git & GitHub
- JavaScript
- jQuery
- Adobe Photoshop

- Bootstrap 4 - Adobe Premiere

- Sass - Slack

LANGUAGES

- English Mother Tongue (C2)
- Mandarin Chinese Fluent (C1)
- Turkish Fluent (B2)

PORTFOLIO

Available at: https://zachdanz.codes

CONTACT

Mobile: +1 (469) 604 4986 Email: zachary.danz@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL CAREER

Corporate Training Facilitator

Zmackworks Training Group | 2017-2019

- Facilitation of corporate training in Shanghai and around Asia
- Leading English and Chinese half and full day workshops
- Run programs promoting critical thinking and problem-solving skills
- Role-play training simulations focused on emotional intelligence

EDU Specialist and Performer

Jiliguala | 2017-2019

- One of the largest Tech Startups in China, with over 9 million users
- Helped develop curriculum, strategy and implementation from scratch
- Acted as main performer in Blues Clues like video series for children
- Co-hosted weekly bilingual English-Chinese podcast

Director of Research and Development

Zmack Global Theatre Group | 2016-2019

- Directed and oversaw all classes in Improv training center
- Became specialist in teaching presentation and soft skills to adults
- Organizer of multicultural events averaging 100 attendees

Head Localizer and Copywriter

Mutantbox | 2016-2017

- Established Tech Company in Shanghai, creating digital games
- Responsible for Chinese-to-English localization
- Social Media Management and SEO-based copywriting

English Teacher/EDU Expert

Various around China | 2013-2016

- Executed lessons, wrote lesson plans, time management
- Regular workshops, creative marketing for centers, recruiting, and more

EDUCATION

Front End Web Developer Tech Degree

Team Treehouse | 2019 - 2020

MA Intercultural Communication

Shanghai Theatre Academy | 2016-2019

BA Theatre Arts

University of the Incarnate Word | 2009-2013